All right let's get started.
Good afternoon everyone ...efforts on the general manager for office
extensibility we're here to drill into some of the things that you heard about this morning in the keynote and cover
it more broadly my partner in crime jeremy...thank am a technical point manager
...office...marketing...show...a showing you
...new announcements kind-of on top of what you saw in the keynote the what would alongside such that I
...of the share with you what we've kind of introduces we lost
...a big land kind of six-month so in ...your great and I think
there's one issue from this morning we wanted to take head-on.
Of anybody saw this as it was going on during the keynote
I myself didn't get to see it so I wasn't quite sure what was going on it's just a couple messages
...communications just a little bit and it was a little bit about drugs and suspect that...seattle has
...legalized no I think they wanted advil but I...it was a little bit of a...mistaken
...cj did own up to...backstage...that he should have been
...the notifications offi had one job and internal.
So,...get that in...but...record my email is not rob...at build demo one-dot on
...it's raw...at microsoft-dot-com if you want
to reach out to me I'd be glad to hear from you so let's dive right in...
So,...talked about this a bunch this morning and
just to recap I think he was quite passionate and quite enthusiastic this is actually a quote that we
have from last fall he truly believes in the future of authors as
a developer platform and in the opportunity
that represents for many different kinds of developers both developers working in
isv are building cloud services but also corporate developers
trying-to delivered great experiences to
in-house employees and there's a couple reasons that that's true one is the
users the office can attract for solutions and...a function in the
...install base and xtraction
and office has as well as the massive growth that we see
in office three sixty five and I know that we've talked about a bunch over the past
months and year but office three sixty five has this reputation as the
...business and microsoft history and,
it is quite an amazing thing to be a part of to really catch that
wave and actually be part of the catalyst of people moving to
the cloud and now on top of that to offer a developer
platform and surface area that people can take advantage of in order to really
drive home not just solutions but solutions helping people be more productive.
So, we've got some ...statistics quantifying what
that actually means just to put a face on what does it mean to be the
fastest-growing business and microsoft history of
is itself has one-point-two billion users and that's office all up that is sort of the full
...area for that actually means is when people when we release new things like
release office for ios android it gets an immediate great amount of attention
and as we wire that up for add-in extensibility becomes a great target market for
you to approach people live in office
...productive...office and this actually means something about the way that they approach
solutions inside of office their serious they're doing business and,
they want to get work done and that actually dramatically changes sort of their profile of
...willingness to invest there's just a ton of data we talked about the api explore and
...the graphic gis we'll talk about that a bunch more right here but just to get a size
for it inside of exchange their over four trillion
emails and office three sixty five of eight hundred-fifty
mating million meetings actually means twenty eight points three meeting million
meetings created every day and this just represents a huge amount of data
in capability...you can take advantage of.
And, with that we...of address the fact the you know,
we have come a long way let me first release the outlook
...with were powerpoint excel and all of you in the rumah fully built the
...add-in so you've written...you've written some...scripts in the past and one thing we
...address was the those things will continue to work in the office clients the we ship on
the windows desktop as you've seen in the keynote where we demonstrated on various
of different vices...forward is...be ready to push more with the app model which we're going to
demonstrate today with the admins for both office and for sharepoint with web apps inside that
...that's really...for us is the will continue to
...that in the office client-but also where you've built things...the ws maybe
...exchangeable full trust code on sharepoint sandbox solutions
...will continue to work in the on premises versions of sharepoint sandbox...continue to work in the
...service but we...guys to look forward to the...new...that
we've push forward with and...where engineering if it is but it will continue to support that
where your isv or your internal customizations and build on what we what we
kind of released of the last ten twenty years and that's really where we kind of moving forward here in the
add-in spice...office sharepoint and with the...as well.
...great so,
this morning such you talked about users in data an...and,
we actually sort of...boiled down even more simply...here's how we talk about the opportunity
and office and the thing that we want you to go do the action so, the first
...talk a bunch about all the users of office this creates a great place to sort of
make your applications discover connect users to your service but, in addition
it really does provide this cross-platform form experience and surface area that you
can...to and as we talk about here that's not just about integrating into office that's also
a building your own apps on top so when we say users the called actions quite clear build
atoms that plug-in the office and you can do that today a bunch
of the things that we talked about in the keynote...here is about the ongoing development this is
an investment area where we were going to keep investing building more and providing more
capabilities...for-you over time the second thing is about all
that data inside the unify api and point inside the
...and making that available so the call the action is actually again quite clear
its connect to office three sixty five api eyes and you'll be able to build
solutions running on mobile devices running on websites...just make it really easy
and great to connect that productivity data one of the things that doesn't show up on this
slide that we think about as critical to how we want to
approach this problem is really making sure that we come to the
developers where they are and we make it super easy for you to do those two things at
inness and calling...and that's why we've really taken approach of making sure that
everything we do is built on open standards using...standards where appropriate
off protocols...author responses are always in json even going a
step further and saying okay if people are going to call these api
...and build mobile apps then they'll need...case running on ios
...so we've built those just little...to make it easy to call the protocol
api and then we went ahead and open-source them as well just
to make it that much easier for people to engage with us the same-store
...story is going to apply to people trying to build more service or server-side
connections talking...api is so we're investing just as much...sure we provide the
riches decays there as well and then the last thing we talked about this morning and
...repeat here is about really going beyond this these are the fundamentals
...over time will bring more intelligence will bring the smarts of the office
graphs and we'll bring you the...can super-power your solutions.
All right let's dive right in and take a look at some office evidence so we'll just stop there a little bit
...the audience kind of like snickering a little bit around this whole
...we've talked about the app model a little bit in the past and we've kind of and sharepoint
apps sharepoint sometimes...ship...apps sometimes...office apps
...apps office in outlook astrophysics so...stumbling block where
we had word apps all of with apps in them
apps enact so access apps so the marketing department sought to stop.
So, that train and from now on will actually be cooling those
attitudes very much roles of the time outlook
...word...so...
Powerpoint...sharepoint allen's so that's the only...address...just move on forwards
...cool...is loaded from the screen if I say apps one more time
...I'm going to get buzzed onstage so robles so we'll see how far we get before we said
it would acts as this point forward excellence...does turn out that it flows pretty naturally
of the tongue and I think everybody understands what we mean the things I do want to talk about is that we've
had...out in the market as I mentioned we started with twenty
thirteen so people can build these things today and really start going and they are seeing
traction one of the beautiful things about working in the cloud and working with always
up-to-date clients is that we really get good rich information about how much
users in usage we're actually gettingand, how much traction we see so,
these are just sharing some of the internal statistics that we've got about end-users jumping on top
of modern at inness ...advantage of it and what we see is ...
the growth curve is exactly the right say that's exactly the right kind of month on
...exponential growth that you want to see we've exceeded three million active users in
a month the growth is an hundred fourteen percent and people are using
and launching these things on a regular basis so that's just for us data and
signals the great...on...something we've got the right kind of adoption happening
now we're just looking for ways to make them even more discoverable and help you is developers plug
even more interesting invaluable add-ons which is what will really drive people want to use this,
yeah, and, as a good example of that we worked with annoys for dot com when we first
...with them on ...web application which we share later on
and the session but one of the highlight here was the double-a significant works integrate with our as
...active directory services so that they can be loaded up in that experience and
we actually put a prototype with...does...who's my car...on the podcast so thank you for
doing this rigid where we one of...demonstrates a new features that
we're releasing inside of the outlook add-in that of office outings we move forward since
I actually release this service with that office...five
...they've actually had aaround over twenty five percent of the new customers are
actually coming signing in from those office free...experiences so...is
...the ecosystems out there is interest from our custom advice to do this now
...thing that I want to show you here which has been shown before is this notion of an add-in, come on,
we had a lot of feedback for use voice site which is available...dot com
...home page and the big thing that we had was when the in the old
world of building for office with the pim...to or you can actually get these toss
...directly on the outlook home page of your experience for the user and you could also have
integration in that ribbon and what you'll notice here is I go through...e-mails in the ribbon here
...the...when I click on that that's...you launch my tossed by directly on the
homepage of outlook allows me to load and html page directly into that tossed...
the has context using the office js javascript api...that email
that I've selected so you'll see here on the screen that in that tossed...they'll do is...
created a meeting and it service and storing that data in it service based on the context of
that email and then the nice thing is and this is the key with all of these
...is I don't have to leave my experience inside outlook wherever I'm running this on one of a
platform I can continue to use outlook but now I can actually use do
the same time in parallel so I can coming here...was that was a little bit of a...of...is
...I mean here I can start adding agendas and we can talk about speakers that are on stage?
And, you know, we can plug that in there and that allows me to kind of have that context and,
jump through now one of the things that was interesting here's what do dot com had some integration
...google what exactly the same thing and the...exports evan...and what richard
did very quickly was actually integrate...one no api which work now we've
office three-six...authentication...means is I can have
...information stored...dot com...one node because I'm going to scribble some notes
...one of my surface or whatever kind of tablet device I have when
I click down here in my one...button here I can go through using the office
...five api with well-known actually slates were...a...that inside of
...in the background that's calling the office...exploitive api trading
that page within my one note that I'm logged into and you'll notice in that corner there's an image...of
...the top there that's coming from the new exchange profile photo api
...we...today as well therefore look over to here on that one
might page for refresh this page?
Was going to jump...one section come back again in my meeting notes
you see now that's actually going created that information that directly my one night so
...that information into yone that pagethe restful
...really simple to use of this means there is I can kind of use the
our of one...to do annotations or...things in a way that may
be is an extension of what I was doing into dot com so this was a prototype...put together
...content show the our of those outlook
...in a way that maybe...considered in the past if there's a couple
...underscore there one is that I'm really excited about this example for combining the two
things together about building at inness and then calling this service api
...to talk a little bit more about this at notion of app commands we're
very excited about going forward we showed you a lot of task...at...
a ribbon...ends like this one or super exciting later on we'll show you some more
in content dead-ends but we think that there's a lot of potential for over time as we build and
invest more in the model for an lighting up new kinds of experiences and types of atoms.
So, the other one of the shown here I'm going to switch for role
...having some devices onstage.
All right so
this is getting back into the sat demo and I want to talk a little bit more about how it's put together and
a little bit more about some of the capabilities that you can light up by taking advantage of
the richer object model that we provide right here and excel and it's just tons of fun to be able to
do this demo directly from within itself the so again this is an add-in that's talking
an sat on prime...using sap gateway
from microsoft really exposes sap data using...and in
...data which makes it super easy for us to consume inside of the microsoft environment and
the simple thing that I can do first it which I showed you this morning
so it's fairly get the data all I'm glad it work this morning.
...like...that's good.
To come back that...conductive ellen...program logo...that was all right.
...so, let's drew back into the sales...demo and show a couple additional things that live
there so what I talked about this morning and the first thing to call out is now I'm going on a
...so this is actually inside of outlook for the
...and we've enabled the same
...model running there so it hopefully it super clear by now how we think about
...how we think about making sure that your solutions are really work
and run everywhere that office runs so let's go ahead and open up the sales
...tab again it's pulling the to in cc information off of the mail thread
...using that to look up the company's inside of sales force and
...opportunities one of the things that I can do that we didn't get to do is really...just
wanted to drive home this notion of taking action in context because this is
the whole value propped...is developers and solution builders is that you can make
sure your users are productive and live-in
...inside the experiences that they love so here I can go ahead and actually
just create this contact for this person that didn't previously exist inside of sales force?
Has gone?
Way connected okay.
Yeah, actually they could have done that and, that would be an interesting enhancement to do since you
are able to refer the to in cc information...excellent look at this.
Let's push the button...super exciting.
Ok, the main thing that I want to show you is that you do have more our and this object model
...detail...a dump some information out of line-of-business system the first thing I might go do is start
to make some changes and this really is the scenario of the exec
on-the-go walking on hall working with this information they go ahead and update the age and
then when they're done with it they can push the compare and save button so now I've been working
inside their spreadsheet and the question is what I done and I do have a
push backed sap to save but before I do that I'd like to check and see
what I did so what we show here is...for nicely formatting the...that I
...was able to go and scan through the entire table selection find the individual cells
that actually been updated in on the right-hand side in a task...go
...notify the users about what was the what was the actual modification
...we think that kind of rich compelling experience really lit up by this service on the back-end
really turns excel into this sort of extension of the end-to-end solution that
...providing
...in addition to that one of the questions we had quite frequently is what whatever happened to
...so we're actually show here is that we've actually involved in up
...realize it was kind of a visual studio browser addition...you to build sharepoint
...office settings without...visual studio locally on your machine because those
...an adding inside offices and
...manifest...that points to website is html and javascript
...this scenario here we've actually logged into nap
...dot com with my microsoft account that might be my outlook dot
...msn dot com for those of you orbit more old-school here and I can log into their
start building...I've already...is very simple is available developers dot com slash code
dashed samples the microsoft buildings at and simply I'm doing...I'm calling a
...a load buildings function if I scroll...the problem I have a
...service I have hosted in asher?
it's going to basically...that json service and render a bunch of buildings in a toss
...my outlook adding and...when I
...that building from that tossed pain is going to injects building
out the html directly into the body my email is simple as
this in javascript I'm grabbing the item of my email that's I'm in context of
...my compose mode within outlook and I'm just simply doing a
...item dot...dot set selected I think...the html
like build-out using the data that's come back from that jason's service...thing about this
snapper experience now is not tides me having to have napa running inside
...is tardy detached you don't need to have that experience and
...I click play here that's going to go encapsulate that website...that forming
the cloud is going to upload the manifests fall into my exchange instance within office
three-six five and what andrew...showing his session later in the
week is how you can actually...outlook home as well as an add-in not
...to exchange...within the office risks five service now if I launch that app is going to
...my experience here within side of office three-six five and
...demonstrate this from the calendar because what this highlights is when I have this
...I mean debug mode here
...create that no event within my calendar and I...this application?
Unload this application here with my...and click on it that's going to go through...that
...wrestle services running...
...list of my buildings on the right-hand side.
And,...get a...buildings obviously all the cool kids within building what yeah.
Where I live we
didn't that you're building yet which is what happens and if I click concert here what you'll
...is the as well as injecting into the body of my email here
the...the building in the bing map image that we had...a hyperlinked so the top with
...get directions other top here
...actually targeted updating location of my meeting event
...simply dom in the code here if I go back to I'm just checking
...if the autumn talk is an appointment I'm actually going to go and
set the location of that meeting invite directly javascript to the building
nine coming from that json response so it's really, really clean
...a web developer this is really easy to get hold of and you don't even need visual studio installed
...machine...damning this from a
...here running in firefox...I have this will debugging...building my first app
...outlook so there's been some huge improvements there on that's sort of
the house to one thing I also one of the points out which we actually did
preview...in october when I go back to my mail here we scold answer
...I've been doing some how shopping recently and someone sent me I've
...myself and email to address and what you'll notice is the we have this outcome
on ball inside of outlook where I can launch my epsilons we showed that with the sows what's
force at exchanges recognize that this is an address and I have a
being maps that is looking if there's...dressy my email I have this concept of a contextual
a link here that allows me to launch that add-in as a pop-pop within that email this
is something we experimented with inside this and you'll see more of these contextual highlights as
we for across our products, yeah, and,
actually this gets back to this notion of making sure that we leave
the users to your service into your solution so when we first shipped
...for outlook...a we call them as relic but this we...them in the
great toolbar and a lot of people didn't notice they were there now you can build add-in dvs that show up
...this highlighted way we were able to see the media increase in adoption
and usage just one thing dimension on that your own contextual
latins can really be keyed off of content in...thread they can have a full regular expression
decide whether or not they hit highlight and, then show up in there now one of the
things that we really want to make sure you walk away from build with is a very clear
picture about what I can go do today what's coming in preview and
...are the things that will be coming down the road and hopefully it's clear from the way we're
having this conversation that we want to be really open about where we're headed and what the future looks
like so this is our attempt to come super clean make it super clear about the
add-in model where currently stands where we're making our investments and what's coming
next so today you can go build these at...they will work across-the-board
and thirty-two...they will largely work in the online
a web apps and as we talked about the demo we are now releasing
...update for excel for that will enable them to run in that environment as well the things
that teams actively working on our making sure that were consistent across the whole family
of ios devices so we pushing hard on that and upcoming months and make to
those updates get into that apple store and in that way
your solution show up across all the ios devices that
your users have and then the very next thing after that which
we're very excited about is really going after the mac and will be able to share some of the framework and infrastructure
...we firmly believe in the vision that these solutions need to run everywhere
that office runs and that offices cross-platform productivity experience
so later this year we'll start work on making sure we get android
and uw a fully enabled and we'll deliver those out
...incremental updates as quickly as we can provide them and that so
that transparent wvu on the how're thinking about the development roadmap?
Yeah, and, the other thing to kinda talk about is the
...and spices...refocusing on where we all with the office...with the
sharepoint...aspect...had a lot of them and...as well as...malicious of others because well, yeah,
and, actually this is an important context for usoffice
...actually they do show up inside of office twenty thirteen so you can
enable them for users that don't actually have office three...sharepoint
...interconnected office three sixty five or connected to an on prime sharepoint installation
we've actually seen the same general shape of curve where we have...this
...growth curve and what we see is were closing in on a billion
necessary who that would be exciting those one of those things that gets we did a million?
Active users for...sharepoint we see fourteen million launches
happening in the month of march and again all of those are driving api calls so these are the
kind of metrics that we're tracking to make sure that the model is doing what we want and
delivering the capabilities for use developers to connect to users...one of the call examples we have here from
a sharepoint perspective is the madison's which you map out about in the past is
actually a microsoft lc...legal team of build something for a particular scenario that was
putting those guys spy jump over here too my hap
...and I launch the medicine or...this is actually using this notion of
legal teams that have matters where they have to store documents and emails of records around a
particular legal topic and they consistently have these things flying around and
...and sharing documents in different ways so what they did was they built this
...dashboard that allowed them to track exactly what was going on with all
that matters so they hosted this all inside
...the leveraging sharepoint is a back-end to store individual matters
...individual site collections so they're all encapsulated the security trimmed a...that has
that contain a feedback and the users can go through and start seeing stacks around things
like what the status of those matters all within the whole organization how much document
shown is going on within each of those individual matters and...as far as using things like the
...services and...biif features...map delay gr locations of those...those
matters are relevance to where they are across the whole of microsoft legal so as an example here of
kind of crossing the boundaries of not just thinking about me myself as a sharepoint developer by
...actually created am and outlook add-in so...I
come into my emails here I have an email where I have an attachment what I launch that add-in what
is going to do is going to use the office js api to notice the there
are actually attachments associated with this email and then there are able to go in here
upload the attachments and decide what matters...
can pick my matter now take into account this is authenticated back into sharepoint but I'm actually
...a in sort of outlook
...indirectly so I...ui...you can see here the with the...on a is pretty
...out here but that would force me to sign into this particular environment and...upload that pick my
...so what we're trying to encourage here is...don't think
these things in silos this demo actually demonstrates lonely and outlook added
...a sharepoint added but also that notion of a web application that's
...inside of the apple...that moyers page and this is something
...actually hosting rightnow internally something
we're looking to share with everyone here as well, yeah, and, let me take a moment
to just be clear about what we're really after because I paid for anyone to walk away thinking I
...that microsoft going into the legal vertical and that's not the goal what we're actually trying to show is that
we're excited about the model and we're excited about the possibilities so we're holding this up
is an internal tool that we built that could not to a bunch of scenarios
...you might have internally but even more importantly as a model for
the best practices around the kinds of things that you can do with the framework we've
delivered and we're working with our best partners inside of this space to make sure that
...light up the same things for them and this really helps,
you know, crystallizes galvanize we're going for the industry all right so
let's flip over and talk about a new kind of application expense a bunch of time talking about
...and how those can connect...sharepoint and sharepoint capabilities but
let's take a step back and talk about the new kid on the block which is just about three sixty
five web apps we first started talking about these last fall and what it
...just a way to easily connect and existing web application that you've
...into office three sixty five and there's a couple reasons that you'd
...do that to make it easy for users to find to make it easy for users to
in and then to use that as a platform that you would want to drive even more
...three sixty five integration so all you really have to do is register your app
in ad and then it shows up in this thing that we have a real name or just keep going...the waffles
...going to...the app...it's the app launcher thank...we have this thing with engineering
...have...internal names I live with and they can never let go of the that's right we have to force
them open-to-the-public outbound so the
easiest way to show up in the app launcher as it says there on the slide is register with active
directory that gets you instantaneously single sign on and that makes it super easy for you to
turn right around and call
...unify api endpoint call...three sixty
five a gis to get access to file mail calendar contact information?
And, in addition we make it super easy-to-use put those things into the
store we continue to invest in not just how do we make the experience great for
users but how can we help your users discover the application there's a bunch of ways that
we like this up one of which is the store in addition we of course have
a corporate catalog where organizations can distribute the own apps that
they care about a few the things that we've made super easy as around first if I want to
acquire one of those new web apps we've made it very easy from within office three sixty five a
ui to go ahead connect to the store find a web app added directly into
my apple launcher the second thing is we've enabled inside the store
functionality for previewing your application so if you'd like to have that kind of targeted
limited audience beta where your producing initial releases...make sure that it works the way you
want to work before you go broaden public wavelet that up and then the last thing is that
where you see this across-the-board it's here with the
stores well really building samples about how we imagine people can do this in this
case a best practices at the demonstrates and,
what great store immigration looks like, yeah, I'm one of the just to show that example of
that store acquisition obviously when you're in office app in the ribbon in the insert
group you'll see the apps and the app...there so you can guide discover those apps for
...outlook excel...powerpoint in the future other things like
...around sway...obviously when you're in the...contents page when you
...and an added...actually get a see the stalling there on that quick launch now
inside of here we'll see now we have the stalling inside the moyer
...so when I'm on the app launch here and I go to my upsetting
had this notion of...if I had to dot com here for instance I can...
in that from my app launches so that no matter where I am inside the web experience obvious three-six
five I can launch those particular apps but now the visibility is a lot
higher to get over to that store and see what apps are available now the
store patient we showed...shows the apps that we can add the web
...we can directly into the...page but also highlights the sharepoint
admins and the office add-in that are available to so we really believe that this
...to our customers your work you been doing to release these things in the
stores wall so for instance
...here...so the docking sign-out you'll see...same experience we had for
...and office outings is now available for those web applications so
if you have a sas service already out there simply add it authenticate with the office
...education and you'll be able to submit this to the store for the
...dashboard become available inside the store as well as a great way to
get exposure into our customer base with
...web application but can do single soil directly from launching landmarks page all the
...more ensure we...there's a really compelling story...of organizations out there?
So, with that I'm going to jump back to the slides.
I'm going to talk a little bit about component so we talked about part of the office at...the
...and this notion of web apps that live within the service one of the...things that
we've started to experience now is this notion of leveraging the sky for business aspects of the
...exploit services
...and to do this virtually jump back so that do dot com scenario which is.
And,...you'll see here is the you may have noticed fewer various
...I launched to dot com here.
In the bottom without one the oracle...we also had a sky-high
...so this...is richer the back to the rumah...me a brand-new e-mail and you'll notice now
...I'm actually seeing...pulling the title I am this meeting was
associated with the conversation id that we had...existing inside of exchange and I can go
through in the meeting options say I want to use scarf as part of this I'll include the
...of the body and include the attachments in that mail as part of that do dot com...
that's in that service right if I jumped over to the...launched dot com from that
...experience I would seal this information but what can actually
the hurt riches ready for this is if I click here on the sky inside this
...we've now launch the do dot com experience in a web browser we've actually got the
...imbed directly inside that...interface that was really neat here
is the on the right-hand side I have to do dot com experience as well so I can be
described cohort without clip...having and starts...different things into this
...again if I just use that experience here of adding my speaker names and,
going through and having some...that I need to make sure I get my make sure I get
...is that all we had a see the directly...you know,
we have both the skylight user interface work and have that communications
going forward as well as the right-hand side being inside my experience more specification
side-by-side?
Now it looks like maybe out wi-fi is not going to
place is always the high-risk high-tension part of are we getting through on wi-fi?
Connecting...actually a couple things I want to interject here what
we're actually using just to make sure everyone gets it such a mentioned briefly this morning
scope has just announced in preview their scope web
sdk and that enables a couple things the first is that you get a bunch of restful
api and javascript...on top of it do basic things like presence
notifications chat and you can just use that directly within the applications that you
build the second part is actually shown here is a plug-in which is allowing you
to embed the sky experience inside of that solution that you build we're
very excited about this as a model for how people think about delivering rich experiences
...sort of the inverse of the add-in but we really want to make sure that where
office has this high-value experience like we have escape that you can use
that to build the target experience that you want to make sure users can be and,
productive without having to leave the context of your solution and what you don't realize
series is that skylight is actually showing richard...a very...without video just doesn't
picked up so, that just shows you where...guy with the imbed aspect we know that in it doesn't always have to be
about being inside our user experience qubit you earning that user experiencing embedding
...stuff in there and that is one example of where we're going with that preview technology...
think now it's time to get on to your most exciting topic...the office...yeah,...so,
this really is as we think about the
...building more momentum lighting up new workloads and having a constant
...of new capabilities that we expose to developers
...we think about this surface area driving new
...and it's great for us because it's very easy for us understand
...being successful and that's when more and more
...being called because that means developers
are building solutions users are enjoying the solutions and getting value out
of them and we're all having impact we want to have so we are really starting to see that fly
...go fourteen point four million daily api calls from...when
...but we're actually seeing is the total up in the billions which means we are really
starting to drive this getting a lot done using api running against
office so I want to flip over here...flip this slide?
Jumping the gun...excited so what we wanted...actually share was that
...a releasing...new api in...we've talked a lot about mail calendar
...files we talk about the ipo in the past...you know, there's lots of other products and services
available office...expired...a demos some other them products
...which we can now integrate directly into the video puerto api
the groups api...demo before and preview and also the one that api which we did show
the do dot com demo earlier on and in the future will actually have
the tossed api as well which we'll talk a little bit more about ignite timeframes and
we have added some additional scenarios based on feedback we got from user voice and from the
...what very closely with to those existing api...released in
...october timeframes...a juror so we're going to show now is
...unify...the we demonstrating the keynote and...going to go through a few more scenarios
...highlight with the api explore which you can actually use...your...
Yeah, and, actually there's another presentation being given tomorrow I think
it ten thirty where they're more into the
unify endpoint and they'll actually using this is a great thing about development
...they'll be using the production environment version of api explore so you get
...we did there where they have nice collapse so
expand on the days on responses and that's pretty cool but, let's take a look we've got here I
...talk a little bit more about the structure of the url that I'm actually making
a request with it's pretty straightforward...dot microsoft dot com that is the name of
unify api endpoints...number in there and as you can see were in previews so it
just says beta but that's where we'll use vone vtwo etc and from there I just go into my
tenant or my individual token such as slash me and I can start to
find entities and drive to edges off of those entities and really navigate the
graph so the first thing is actually that I can just run a query call users
in this is actually doing what you would expect which is give-me back all the users in
my active directory of course it's helping us to page through them since we don't get overwhelmed
and responses reasonable but the thing I did this morning
...is exactly corresponds to one
...common scenarios is...me filter this down help me write a query so we support a notion
of attributes that you can query on in this case filter equals department and then there's
filter on where the department is equal to operations so we'll run that get back
...set of results and then let's just scan down and start to feel pretty
confident that in fact we're getting back the results that we would want to see their and
...highlight the graphing this
...from that collection to an individual user every object in the
graph actually gets a unique and persistent id so this is a huge advantage
in terms of thinking about how can I make sure I can get a placeholder so can always get back to that object
...time even if it moves around so I can take advantage of that
...this individual user and then from there as we
talk about this morning super easy to just drill instantaneously in the files
...ok now again?
We've got this persistent...idea which I can navigate to get to the file and
let's just think a look at some of the properties that you find off of there one of the most interesting things is the
last modified by so again driving home this notion of graphs and
...navigation going from node edge I can go from the file
define the last modified by get the...from that username get all
of their files et cetera et cetera and it's really easy to drive-through
this experience seamlessly moving back and forth...across.
Different workloads on the back-end without having to worry about howmicrosoft's running
...cloud huts...it's workloads another icy with actually work with...smart sheet
so we started with them with the...the notion of integrating with their web app so that they could have that
single-source experience directly from the apple join the
...page and but one of a product they've got...map the work
...all the kind of agencies...look...within
narrowness service which is to do with storing all the rows within their own sheets and
draws it on this beautiful map connecting although sheets that are related as well as
...people involved in them but I've taken this of step further you
can actually jump into these individual case studies which are sheets within the smart
sheets ecosystem world when I click on the sheets a and say get the data from office three-six
...well that's...she can do is going to map that data.
Directly from inside their world against the relations of what's inside the office
three-six five world slushy demonstrate here the we can grab the males
...related to that particular sheets
the foils and the contact so if I go in...maybe the
...summary sheets from the inside this work map here you'll see that
jaime o'donnell down the bottom here has been
selected in their work map now the nice part here is...used that unify api
and point to actually...back through to filter through office
...five from this uses inbox what...of come from
jayne o'donnell related to the are...sheet that we have so you can see here all the
e-mails...to that particular project large selected and if I school over to another
plane here you actually see it will do the same thing regarding grab all of the related files one
drive...business...that particular she has been captured inside the sm
...ecosystem again in a really nice user interface
...of the covers this is just using that what in point
...that information through and I can go through further here and scroll
...the right-hand side here and see that is pulling for those calendar events
...to...gives me this view...not only of what small
...data...within their service but also...all that intelligence...we still within office
...five allowing these business used to be a lot more productive data
...enjoying that into one single view slave authenticated in one-seat
...same time smart should on the covers can call through to...unify api and pull
...information up and use it within their user interface so we're not forcing the use
of jump between concepts of being inside smart she and then being inside
of that experience so that's a really cool demo the we going deeper...some of the
...sessions during the week which will...the session one thing I'd like to call out about that none of the
smarts you guys are excited about this page you can see this user experience that pulls it all together and the
user is living in smart sheet and navigating across office three sixty five but,
because...hits is very high
bar around compliance and data security is a big deal for smarty to know they don't
have the persist all that data because at that point they be have to worry about a bunch of issues that office three
...takes care of so the organizational hierarchy the documents the
males they all live in office three sixty five another example here is something we...
in october which was this notion of a property manager property inspector we ship this app
...a web application we opensource the code on get how but we also actually
...and ios native application using the...to communicates those office
...five api in points?
Later in the year we actually ships accord over mobile application
...application and I android naive applications so no matter what you one of the right
a mobile app you can see how we build these things would open-source the whole thing now this connects
...different endpoints waivers mail calendar contacts and also
foils one thing that we're announcing today.
If I go down to need...a look at one of these properties is that what I jump into an individual property
we've also created this notion now that every single property has a
...unify group associated with it and
unify group gets a bunch of agencies around the ingredients are here
...about it at ignite where it's all about files...all about a shared
camden for that group is about the members of the group and also the files and also
things like videos so you can see here on the right-hand side that I have a bunch of members of this property
that's been driven by this notion of unify group if I click on seymour here
and launch that when you go over into...experience
inside outlook we take a look at these groups you'll get a see here these are the members of that
group and if I go over to firewalls or conversations or calendar in the example
where in october with a story in the uses calendar was there when we do
repair as or inspections...storing inspections inside the groups
caroline's everyone has visibility and you have the ability as an individual
...subscribe to this calendar which means any events
...calendar will appear inside your own individual calendar as well
...gone further than that because obviously we have all the one notes as well so when we one of
maybe take photos of inspections...want to annotate over maybe the broken pipe or
...that's been going on you can do that within that one that experience on your surface but also we
have the video footage so this property for instance has a leaky
...so on the video portal...you can get noun the iphone and the android someone's
...the repair guys actually gordon recorded that property had a leaky top
...into the video portal...adj...media streaming services and that's
...this notion of unify group within the office
...five experience but the beauty is that you can be used within the out-of-the-box office
...five group experience where we have this notion of conversations around
the properties and follows around the properties and loads around the properties or we
can have the experience directly inside the...property manager app which is being
hosted adjthis one for instance...written with...nbc leveraging all those
library libraries and unify api to bring this up into your own
...user interface so again it's all about pulling together these all the experiences you
have an office...five into one and solution and if you guarded depth office dot com.
And, in the resources section of the top.
And, you go to code samples here you actually get...go and directly...from get hop so
if I just wait for this to load up and if I just search for the property inspect.
For can spell and if I go view here you'll see old instructions on how you can get this
running your own develop...and if I go seeing get...actually...clone this
...down here and you'll notice...zoom in here you see that there's that native android app
there is a called over...napa native ios apps there as well as well as the astra
...so this is...demo that will do a lot more talking about in top...secession later
on in the week where...look deeper into how we build those things with
...mobile apps and that...web application launch from the app launcher.
There was one lost every one of the show so I'm going to
...unlock the iphone...you've got the from print...you're going to let my
Diverges switch
...up...so this is another quick look at another sample that
we've written and you can kinda see how our methodology goes at this point we've written
the code we produced an application and then we're going to go put it up on get hub actually I think they re
...live this week it's great so, you can download this and see what we did and build
the exactly the same kind of thing even take these ideas and enhance them the notion here
is that boy when I'm on the road there's a few key conversations if you keep people I want to keep track
of...if I open up my mail inbox I am ...to
a stress and panic about twenty thousand things going on I didn't want to know about so this app is called email
...and what it does is just give me a filtered view of what's coming on so I can just
do the writing by the family and only pay attention to a specific set of conversations what you see
actually...some nice ios ui that we've built ... swiping but,
the key thing is that this is going against the office three sixty-five api...to get the contents
my inbox...a bunch of easy-to-use settings like hey let's take a look at
...that are coming from these particular senders or to drill in on particular conversations that
I want to look at it makes it easy for me decide whether or not I want to toggle the read on read status
inside outlook and...just show me the on read messages are justurgent
messages and you get this kind of rich...experience and it's fairly snappy running against
...production api so we hope you take a look and go in for more stuff...
the nice thing here is when you launch that email actually have the ability to do it follows so I can say I want to
...this particular conversation or maybe because...I'm in a...
anything coming from jeremy will always show up in my...you...you can see the case the
...can kind of customize that entitle as you will now let's actually open-source srs native
application...you get a grab that down there and play with that you will?
So, lastly as we wrap up for the session here we wanted to talk about was how you
can get started now you would have seen the office receives five
...you...into the building today one thing we're actually announcing today is...developer
program launchwhat this will give you if you go and sign up for this program is you'll
become a...will be in this kind of network of how will communicate moving forward into
all the notifications on any new announcements we do around new endpoints all-new
...and new app commands were released into that feature we had a lot of great feedback from you
guys the...was quite hard to keep up...of the provided channel you could subscribe to keep up with
that information will also give you a one-year three office
...develop attendant which previously you...to
have paid for as part of that sign up experience as well as being to go and do a lot of free
...available in-depth office dot com slash training an additional handle labs
...provide purely for that dedicated program will also provide tools and...got to
announcements I have some tools will have available to...as part that sign up experience and
...doing monthly web laws where you get to hear from...out team...here and cj of
self and...and engineers as well talking about new features where your as part of that
program will continue that dialogue with the ongoing so you can go and sort of that program now
...depth office dot com slash...is more information if you want to hear about it on abu
...the ground full level so the first three tools were actually going to give you as part of that program?
The first one is the to...ui which...javascript framework which is available
...give you a one-year three pro license for that as part of the signing up for the...things
a pretty good through...in addition to that another thing that we hear from isv is the
we...atta have the same clinic communication with our uses...if you sign up
...com for instance as a sas author a few days if you're not actually using
this service the service will actually email your remind you that there's some
recall features within the sas product and you're probably had that familiar experience of a
...you signed up for the positive ready forgot...subscribe to them and,
this thing kind of reminds you and...various different points in time that reaches out
...dot com provides that services world...going to...a basic one-year subscription
for-you as part of...experiences audio festive program as well so
overtime will give additional licenses with different things as we go through we
...encourage you to kind of jump on board to this their program and,
take advantage of these three things we're going to give you as part of that experience.
So, with that one of the clear up as part of this was we have demo
...today there are some resources sessions the wrestle we're...the print
some is experiences what role did you want to kind of explain what things we've released today
...prayer thank you for that
...this is back to this notion of we wanted to be really clear and really concrete so that, you know,
what to go do today and which things to play around with so that
you ready for what's happening tomorrow tomorrow and over coming months so,
one of the things that I didn't talk about that actually
...get into tomorrow is this notion of course support so
it's very common pattern for people writing single page apps and be able to need to get to these api
...a different domain and we are lighting that up across those three
sixty five api so now it's really easy to build those bars...
word extending the notion of app only permissions within our off of flo the
context highlighting the drive more users into your apps and you can already do today
add inness inside of word and excel and I think people have seen the demo for turns
...as well as outlook so really reaching out to that notion of cross-platform
...the tenet list...jeremy the demoed and we've updated all the
...to be current with the latest reads of the api is but there's a bunch of stuff coming,
coming and we really think about this is constant rolling thunder we're not going to hold back we're going to
get out and engages often as possible...here's what's new here's where we're goingso,
the unify api is a great tool for developers
we're very excited to bring that onboard still and...please take a look one of the things
is really important coming forward is this notion of web wghooks because it's great that you can write apps that
...services but of course you want to be notified when something interesting is
happening the first-place will wire that up is inside of the exchange api
is will be making that available consistently and broadly going up from there
I talked to this morning in the keynote about the desired to align consumer
and commercial api is if you saw the recent release of one drive api
...on the consumer side you'll notice that they're really consistent with how the one
drive stuff works in one drive for
business and the goal is that will bring all of those together and as we get the offload
...into one place it becomes very easy to write apps that works seamlessly across the
...just...close out a few the others we have file handlers and sharepoint that we've demo
...couple times and we'll be talking about more this
week making it easy to...a new kind of add-in that lets it, you know,
if you have a new file type you can make that edible and actionable for within sharepoint and within outlook
...big news on consumer commercial convergence is actually making sure you can write
...that work for outlook dot com so they will show up inside of the consumer
spaces well we talked about commands in the ribbon more visual studio twenty
fifteen tooling and again, on enhancements to the java sdk and js
plugins yes so we...to leave you today is part of this session was really we can go
away from and...from this session which is essentially the
...sign up to develop a programme...a lot of business there you get for
free I would encourage as well as
...sessions that are available in these major rooms is we're doing a significant amount of expressed
...color ten-minute nugget talks downstairs all now office...five
...and leaders in the space of in building...three-six by for...while now and that gives you a bit of
...an idea of what's going on those programs we go general...booth you gotta go and see the schedules
there as well which are actually available...slides if you would like one of these qualities
...you send you doi myself...robles stage here and you should really what...of these
...you will need to do is going grab that...from downstairs in the both and
...the back of the room is like wheeling and having those out and if you go
...stations on the boots and you have follow the hands-on labs and you check out one of those
expressed sorts will put a stamp in your leaflets and you gotta get a
who'd is suitable or stickers now in addition to that?
We do have some really cool sessions this week we were just kind of...on some of the ones that myself
...most excited about as...movie demo today so that...feed...going to the
...the tomorrow eleven thirty if you have a chance to go by that would really be the place to get a
detailed understanding of the whole range of things will be able to do with unify api
endpoint, yeah, we have topic
...talking about that property...scenario where who go into the web applications their
additions that during brand the same sessions me talking about the fall handlers and then and
...be talking about those...and outlooks who go a lot deeper into those outlook at
inness a and both on the alamo comment also it
...exchange ...maps what should be doing a great tool called out how we've
all the store and how you can get involved in building apps with store both the office adding sharepoint
...those web applications and, also ...is doing
...friday talking about angular applications and, how you can build those
...leverage those inside those office at internship what...and those web applications I can see a lot
of our speakers in a room pointing at themselves going moi sectional that there are a
...of other sessions available here I can see...but he's going to have a...parity faceless
...if I don't mention role powered sessions on the api as well because he doesn't
...job of...look like a complete fool and fiddler because he makes it
way too easy so I will just give him...of the head and only express
talks are available and there's a leaflets will those timing's there...great ones there
...people like alex more brian harper...a dabbling so if you've ever done...work
...a great two-column on types...their one-year-olds remember
...office dot com...one place to go...sort of the program is of eighty hours
...training if you're not sick of my voice myself a...a...the back of the room
do a weekly pop cost...available android iphone and windows phone we can go
...to updates essentially I run around campus and stick a microphone
...great early questions...another good way of keeping up with that
...site thanks-very-much and thanks robo your in the key this morning or appreciate onstage
...is great confusion opportunity and...will be downstairs for the rest of the wakes if you
have questions please feel free to gravis and getting...dot com thanks
...thank you?